<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>

<elements>
<info>
    <update version="0.0.1">
        <file name="background-collector.xml"
    url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jaydecahedron/what-we-do-together/main/background/collector.xml" />
    </update>
</info>
</elements>

	<element name="Collector" type="Background" source="HOMEBREW_WWDITS" id="ID_BACKGROUND_COLLECTOR_WWDITS">
		<description>
			<p>You have spent your time as a vampire collecting items of materialistic importance.</p>
			
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong>Insight, Religion</li>
				<li><strong>Languages:</strong>Two of your choice</li>
				<li><strong>Equipment:</strong>One wondrous item (Stone of Good Luck, Cloak of Protection, Hat of Disguise, or Pearl of Power), a vial of ancient blood or energy, an artifact from the year you became a vampire, a famous piece of artwork that features yourself in the piece of work, and a belt pouch containing 15 gp</li>
			    <li><strong>Vial of Ancient Blood | Vial of Ancient Energy:</strong>Refills a variable amount of times until it’s magic is lost. Roll 1d20 to refill the vial - DC is 1 through 20 with each successful refill increasing the DC by 1. If you have bless, you may use bless on this roll. Use this blood or energy to feed.</li>
            </ul>
			<div element="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_FINDERS-KEEPERS" />
			<h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
			<p>As a collector, items of materialistic import call your attention and you are able to gain additional insight about objects you are inspecting. You have been collecting items throughout your time as an immortal creature of the night and you have amassed a wide variety of items that you no longer remember everything you have. If you are ever in need of a less common item, it’s possible to find such an item in your collection.

If you see an item you wish to collect, you have advantage on either one persuasion or one sleight of hand roll. You might also have ties to artists, collectors, and traders that can help you locate material objects of interest. If you remain on good terms within these communities of connection, you may find yourself gifted items without request or payment.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">Insight, Religion, 2 Languages</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION" />
			<select type="Language" name="Language (Collector)" number="2" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
			<grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_FINDERS-KEEPERS" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
			<select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
			<select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
				<item id="1">I like to collect a single type of object and constantly talk about my collected items.</item>
				<item id="2">I can find common ground between the fiercest enemies, bargaining  with them an item from my collection in an attempt of peaceful recourse.</item>
				<item id="3">I see omens in every item of my collection. The gods try to speak to us, we just need to listen.</item>
				<item id="4">I wish to add anything and everything to my collection. Nothing is of no value.</item>
				<item id="5">I know almost nothing about the items in my collection and often lie or make up stories about their origins or history.</item>
				<item id="6">I am very selective about the items in my collection. Items must meet a rigorous amount of requirements.</item>
				<item id="7">I collect my items to destroy them. I believe the universe needs to be rid of these objects.</item>
				<item id="8">I've spent so long amongst the objects, admiring and appraising my collection, that I have little practical experience dealing with others.</item>
			</select>
			<select type="List" name="Ideal">
				<item id="1">Tradition. The ancient objects must be preserved and understood. (Lawful)</item>
				<item id="2">Charity. I always try to share my collection, no matter what the personal cost. (Good)</item>
				<item id="3">Passion. I must show everyone the true value of my collection. (Chaotic)</item>
				<item id="4">Power. I hope to one day use my collection to advance beyond my peers. (Lawful)</item>
				<item id="5">Peace. I trust that my collection will help us find paths to peace. (Lawful)</item>
				<item id="6">Aspiration. I seek to prove myself worthy with all that I collect. (Any)</item>
			</select>
			<select type="List" name="Bond">
				<item id="1">I would die to recover an ancient relic that was lost long ago.</item>
				<item id="2">I will someday rid the world of evil.</item>
				<item id="3">I owe my life to a fellow collector that saved me from a cursed existence.</item>
				<item id="4">Everything I do is for my fellow Creatures of the Night.</item>
				<item id="5">I will do anything to protect my collection.</item>
				<item id="6">I seek to preserve what others seek to destroy.</item>
			</select>
			<select type="List" name="Flaw">
				<item id="1">I judge others harshly, and myself even more severely.</item>
				<item id="2">I could easily lose myself in my collection if given the chance.</item>
				<item id="3">My piety sometimes leads me to blindly trust those that profess their love of my collection.</item>
				<item id="4">I am inflexible in my thinking.</item>
				<item id="5">I am suspicious of strangers and expect the worst of them.</item>
				<item id="6">Once I pick a goal, I become obsessed with it to the detriment of everything else in my life.</item>
			</select>
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Feature: Finders Keepers" type="Background Feature" source="HOMEBREW_WWDITS" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_FINDERS-KEEPERS">
		<supports>Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As a collector, items of materialistic import call your attention and you are able to gain additional insight about objects you are inspecting. You have been collecting items throughout your time as an immortal creature of the night and you have amassed a wide variety of items that you no longer remember everything you have. If you are ever in need of a less common item, it’s possible to find such an item in your collection.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you see an item you wish to collect, you have advantage on either one persuasion or one sleight of hand roll. You might also have ties to artists, collectors, and traders that can help you locate material objects of interest. If you remain on good terms within these communities of connection, you may find yourself gifted items without request or payment.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Finders Keepers" />
	</element>
</elements>
